<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Medalert</string>
    <string name="symptoms">Anemia - Low healthy red blood cell count \n
-Tiredness \n
-Weakness \n
-Pale \n
-Feel faint \n
-Shortness of breath \n
Take iron or folic acid supplements. \n \n


Depression - Extreme sadness during pregnancy or after birth \n
-Intense sadness \n
-Irritability \n
-Appetite changes \n
Therapy, support groups, medicines \n \n


Ectopic pregnancy - A fertilized egg implants outside of the uterus, usually in the fallopian tube. \n
-Abdominal pain \n
-Shoulder pain \n
-Vaginal bleeding \n
-Dizziness \n
Drugs or surgery used to remove the ectopic tissue \n \n


Gestational diabetes - Blood sugar levels too high during pregnancy \n
-Extreme thirst \n
-Extreme hunger \n
-Fatigue \n
Follow healthy meal plan from health care professional \n \n


Hyperemesis gravidarum- Extreme sickness during pregnancy \n
-Nausea \n
-Vomiting \n
-Weight loss \n
-Appetite loss \n
-Dehydration \n
-Fainting \n
Dry bland foods and fluids or prescribed medicines \n \n


Miscarriage - Pregnancy loss from natural causes before 20 weeks \n
-Vaginal spotting \n
-Vaginal bleeding \n
-Cramps \n
-Abdominal pain \n
-Vaginal fluid \n \n


Placenta previa - Placenta covers part or entire opening of cervix inside of the uterus \n
-Vaginal bleeding \n
Cut back on activity level and increase bedrest. May require hospitalization. \n \n


Placental abruption - Placenta separates from uterine wall, fetus cannot get enough oxygen \n
-Vaginal bleeding \n
-Cramping \n
-Abdominal pain \n
-Uterine tenderness \n
In minor separation, bed rest may stop the bleeding. Severe cases can require immediate \n
medical attention. \n \n


Preeclampsia - High blood pressure and problems with kidneys and other organs starting after
20 weeks of pregnancy \n
-High blood pressure \n
-Swelling \n
-Too much protein in urine \n
-Stomach pain \n
-Blurred vision \n
-Dizziness \n
-Headaches \n
May need medicines and bed rest at home or in hospital \n \n


Preterm labor - Going into labor 37 weeks of pregnancy \n
-Increased vaginal discharge \n
-Pelvic pressure \n
-Cramping \n
-Back pain \n
-Contractions \n \n


Bacterial vaginosis - Vaginal infection caused by an overgrowth of bacteria normally found in the
vagina \n
-Grey or white discharge \n
-Burning when urinating \n
-Itching \n
Antibiotics treat BV \n \n


Cytomegalovirus - Common virus that can cause disease in infants whose mothers are infected with CMV \n
-Mild illness \n
-Fever \n
-Sore throat \n
-Fatigue \n
-Swollen glands \n
Good hygiene. Antiviral drugs for infants. \n \n


Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) - Viral infection that can be passed to baby during birth. \n
-Nausea \n
-Vomiting \n
-Diarrhea \n
-Dark urine \n
-Pale bowel movements \n
-White eyes \n
-Yellowing skin \n
Lab tests and vaccination. \n
Influenza - Common viral infection which pregnant women are susceptible to \n
-Fever \n
-Cough \n
-Sore throat \n
-Runny nose \n
-Muscle pain \n
-Aches \n
-Tiredness \n
-Vomiting \n
-Diarrhea \n
Vaccinations and antiviral medicine \n \n


Listeriosis - Infection with the harmful bacteria listeria, can cause early delivery or miscarriage. \n
-Fever \n
-Muscle aches \n
-Chills \n
-Diarrhea \n
-Nausea \n
-Severe headache \n
-Stiff neck \n
Avoid foods harbouring listeria, antibiotics. \n \n


Parvovirus B19 - Virus can infect the fetus, raises risk of miscarriage and can cause severe anemia \n
-Fever \n
-Tiredness \n
-Rash \n
-Painful joints \n
-Swollen joints \n
Blood transfusions mightt be needed for people with immune system issues or red blood cell disorders \n \n


Urinary tract infection (UTI) - Bacterial infection in urinary tract, can cause preterm labor \n
-Burning when urinating \n
-Frequent urination \n
-Pelvis pain \n
-Back pain \n
-Stomach pain \n
-Side pain \n
-Shaking \n
-Chills \n
-Fever \n
-Sweats \n \n


Yeast infection - Infection caused by an overgrowth of bacteria normally found in the vagina \n
-Vaginal itch \n
-Vaginal swelling \n
-Vaginal redness \n
-Vaginal burning \n
-Painful urination \n
-White vaginal discharge \n
Vaginal creams and suppositories are used to treat yeast infection when pregnant. </string>
</resources>
